Guide to the Thomas W. Streeter Collection of Texas Manuscripts
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Personal Files, 1787-1882, WA MSS S-498
  - Royall, Richardson Royster, 1798-1840
    - ALS to Henry Smith, Caney, 1834 Nov 14 (Box 4, Folder 225)
      Discusses a local election.
    - 2 ALS to Ira R. Lewis, Caney, 1838 Nov 1 (Box 4, Folder 226)
      Second item dated 1837 on docket.
      2 p. 20.5-24 cm.
      Discusses business matters.
  - San Antonio, Texas. Citizens
    - Draft of Memorial to the congress of the free State of Coahuila and Texas, San Jacinto, 1832 Aug 28 (Box 4, Folder 227)
      Asking that the Law of Jan 31,
      1831 dividing the Department of
      Bexar be repealed.
  - Saucedo, Jose Antonio
    - ALS to Stephen F. Austin, Bexar, Texas, 1825 Jun 2 (Box 4, Folder 228)
      Writes that the Governor has ac-
      cepted his recommendation of Austin
      to be chief of the Department be-
      tween Nacogdoches and the frontier.
  - Scott, John
    - ALS to Mrs. Eunice Parker, Vincennes, Ind, 1838 Mar 11 (Box 4, Folder 229)
      Enclosed: ALS from Dr. Barton to
      John Scott.
      1838 Mar 9, n.p.
      Concerns information about George
      D. Parker.
  - Seguin, Erasmo, 1782-1857
    - ALS to Stephen F. Austin, Bexar, Texas, 1832 Apr 23 (Box 4, Folder 230)
      Asks that Austin urge the
      colonists to declare their
      adherence to the government
      of their adopted country.
    - ALS to Samuel Williams, Bexar, Texas, 1832 Oct 10 (Box 4, Folder 231)
      Asks about the Texas Convention.
  - Seguin, John Nepomuceno, 1806-1889
    - Report concerning Mexican troops across the Rio Bravo, San Antonio, 1840 Dec 12 (Box 4, Folder 232)
      3 p. 26 cm.
  - Simpson, William
    - ALS to "Dear Sir", Gonzales, Texas, 1835 Apr 9 (Box 4, Folder 233)
      2 p. 24 cm.
      With typescript and photostat.
      Tells of murders by the Indians.
  - Singleton, Stanley
    - ALS to Felix Huston, Hardinsburg, 1836 Jan 1 (Box 4, Folder 234)
      Gives details of the sale of his
      [Huston] brother's property.
  - Smith, Henry, 1784-1851
    - ALS to John A. Wharton, Brazoria, Texas, 1832 Nov 4 (Box 4, Folder 235)
      2 p. 19.5 cm.
      About a quarrel with Wharton's
      brother.
    - ALS to "Honble the President and Members of the Council," n.p, 1836 Jan 12 (Box 4, Folder 236)
      Apologizing for his language in a
      previous letter.
    - ALS to Ira R. Lewis, San Felipe de Austin, Texas, 1836 Feb 21 (Box 4, Folder 237)
      Granting Lewis a leave of absence
      from the government.
    - ALS to Samuel Houston, Houston, Texas, 1837 Jun 21 (Box 4, Folder 238)
      1 p. 28.5 cm.
      Biographical note on verso signed
      Harriet Gillette Smith Fulton.
      Asks that he be granted a leave of
      absence.
  - Smith, John William, 1792-1845
    - ALS to Ira R. Lewis, Bexar, Texas, 1835 Apr 28 (Box 4, Folder 239)
      Discusses current political topics.
  - Smyth, George Washington, 1803-1866
    - 2 ALS to Ira R. Lewis, Austin, 1850 Jun 15 (Box 4, Folder 240)
      Second item dated 1851 Jun 27.
      Relates to various land matters.
  - Somervell, Alexander, 1796-1854
    - ALS to M.A. Bryan, Bordentown [sic], 1839 Sep 4 (Box 4, Folder 241)
      Asks that they delay their
      business dealings.
    - Articles of agreement for a partnership with Moses Austin Bryan, n.p, 1840 Jan 22 (Box 4, Folder 242)
      Signed: A. Somervell, M. Austin
      Bryan.
    - ALS to M.A. Bryan, San Felipe de Austin, Texas, 1841 Feb 14 (Box 4, Folder 243)
      Asking Bryan to go into business
      with him.
    - ALS to M.A. Bryan, Peach Point, 1841 Mar 3 (Box 4, Folder 244)
    - ALS to M.A. Bryan, San Felipe de Austin, Texas, 1841 Jul 12 (Box 4, Folder 245)
      Discusses business conditions.
    - ALS to "Sub-prefecto de la Villa de Guerrero," Campo General Orilla derecha del Rio Grande, 1842 Dec 17 (Box 4, Folder 246)
      2 p. 28.5 cm.
      Asks that he be paid 5000 pesos
      for his army.
  - Stapp, William Preston
    - ALS to Ira R. Lewis, Texana, 1838 Aug 3 (Box 4, Folder 247)
      Concerns politics.
  - Stewart, Charles Bellinger, 1806-1885
    - ALS to Ira R. Lewis, Montgomery, 1838 Oct 5 (Box 4, Folder 248)
      4 p. with address, 24.5 cm.
      Asking for some legal advice.
  - Sullivan, I.S.
    - ALS to Felix Huston, Richmond Fort Bend Co, 1842 Mar 23 (Box 4, Folder 249)
      Post-script note dated
      1842 Mar 24, Houston.
      Discusses military news.
  - Swartwout, Samuel, 1783-1856
    - ALS to Ira R. Lewis, New York, 1836 Jul 3 (Box 4, Folder 250)
      Concerns recent political events
    - Signed invitation to a dinner given by "The Friends of Texas," n.p, 1836 Jul 16 (Box 4, Folder 251)
      3 p. 19.5 cm.
      Signed: Samuel Swartwout and
      G.W. Curtis.
      Reply of p.3 signed Henry Ogden.
      Two newspaper clippings pasted on
      p.1 and p.2.
      Enclosed notes on Swartwout.
    - ALS to John Randolph Lewis [sic], New York, 1837 Feb 6 (Box 4, Folder 252)
      in Texas and annexation.
  - Tamaulipas, Mexico. Governor (Acting) 1835 (Samano)
    - Full name: Jose Guadalupe de Samano
      - Copy of contract for colonization between Racknitz and the state of Tamaulipas, Ciudad Victoria, 1835 Apr 10 (Box 5, Folder 253)
        Signed: Jose Guadalupe de Samano,
        Francisco Villasenor, acting
        Governor and Chief Officer, and
        Baron Juan Racknitz.
        Accompanide by typed translation.
  - Texan Santa Fe Expedition, 1841
    - Copy of General Order No. 1, Head Quarters, Santa Fe Pioneers, 1841 May 24 (Box 5, Folder 254)
      Signed: Hugh McLeod and Theodore
      Sevey, Adjutant.
      Orders to mobilize.
    - Copy of General Order No. 5, Head- quarters, Santa Fe Pioneers, 1841 Jun 9 (Box 5, Folder 255)
      1 p. 23 cm.
      Orders to be prepared to march on
      the following day.
  - Texas (Provisional government). General Council
    - Resolution to have James Bowie raise all the troops he can, San Felipe de Austin, Texas, 1835 Dec 29 (Box 5, Folder 256)
      Signed: James W. Robinson and E.M.
      Pease.
    - Resolution to appoint James Fanning [sic] and F.W. Johnson as agents to raise troops for the government, n.p, 1836 Jan 7 (Box 5, Folder 257)
      Signed: James W. Robinson, Lt. Gov.
      and ex officio Pr. of the Gen.
      Council and Edw. B. Wood, Secretary
      pro tem of the General Council.
    - Resolution concerning Henry Smith, n.p., 1836 Jan 12 (Box 5, Folder 258)
      Signed: J.D. Clements, Chairman
      and R.R. Royall.
      At end: Unanimously adopted in
      General Council Assembled at San
      Felipe de Austin this 12 January
      1835 - John McMullen, Prest. Pro
      tem of General Council and E.W.
      Cullen Secty pro tem.
  - Texas (Prov. gov't). Governor, 1835-1836 (Smith)
    - ADS to "The People of Texas...", San Felipe de Austin, Texas, 1835 Dec 28 (Box 5, Folder 259)
      Appointing Sam Houston, John
      Forbes, and John Cameron
      commissioners to treat with the
      Indians.
    - DS to James Kerr, John J. Linn, George Sutherland, and R.M. William- son, San Felipe de Austin, Texas, 1836 Jan 8 (Box 5, Folder 260)
      Accompanied by leaf with a note of
      the appointment dated 1835 Nov 13,
      San Felipe de Austin and certified
      by Edward B. Wood, 1836 Jan 8.
      Appointing them to carry into full
      effect the 14th Article of the
      organic law in the Department of
      Bexar.
  - Texas (Republic). Army
    - Company orders. San Patricio 3 o'clock p.m. 6th Nov. 1835, 1835 Nov 6 (Box 5, Folder 261)
      Concerns the military funeral of
      Marsalino Garcia.
  - Texas (Republic) Congress. House of Representatives
    - Resolution to thank Waddy Thompson, Percy W.Doyle, and Mr. Packenham [sic] for their interest in the Tex- an prisoners in Mexico, Washington, 1843 Dec 22 (Box 5, Folder 262)
      Signed: Richardson Surry, Speaker
      of the House and Ja. H. Raymond,
      Chief Clerk.
  - Texas (Republic) Dept. of State
    - ALS "To Chairm. joint comt. on enrolled Bills", Columbia, 1836 Dec 19 (Box 5, Folder 263)
      Signed: Stephen Fuller Austin.
      Notification of the law providing
      for boundary definition.
    - ALS to M.A. Bryan, Washington, Texas, 1843 Jul 28 (Box 5, Folder 264)
      Concerns an exchange of lands.
    - ALS to Henry Smith, Washington, Texas, 1843 Aug 16 (Box 5, Folder 265)
      Concerns the negotiation of a peace
      treaty between Texas and Mexico.
  - Texas (Republic) President, 1836-1838 (Houston)
    - LS to "Gentlemen of the Senate and House of Representatives," Columbia, Texas, 1836 Oct 25 (Box 5, Folder 266)
      At top of p. 1: Confidential.
      Transmitting letters from Andrew
      Jackson and himself.
    - Signed commission appointing John P. Coles Chief Justice of Washington County, Columbia, 1836 Dec 20 (Box 5, Folder 267)
      Signed: S.F. Austin, Secretary of
      State.
  - Texas (Republic) President, 1838-1841 (Lamar)
    - Letter to "The Honorable The House of Representatives," Austin, 1840 Jan 27 (Box 5, Folder 268)
      At end: A true copy, [signed] David
      G. Burnet, Sec. of State.
      Gives reasons for rejecting the
      bill, "An act to detect fraudulent
      Land Certificates and to provide
      for issuing patents to legal
      claimants."
  - Texas (Republic) President, 1841-1844 (Houston)
    - ALS (facsimile) to William Bryan, Washington, 1843 Jan 24 (Box 5, Folder 269)
      4 p. 27 cm.
      Last two pages: Signed list dated
      1843 Jan 26.
      At end: printed statement signed
      Thos. J. Green, October 1855.
    - LS to Isaac Van Zandt, Washington, 1844 Jan 29 (Box 5, Folder 270)
      5 p. 28,5 cm.
      At top: Confidential.
      Letter finished on Feb 15, 1844.
      Accompanied by a negative
      photostat.
      Concerns instructions about the
      annexation of Texas to the United
    - LS to G.W. Hill, Houston, 1844 Apr 6 (Box 5, Folder 271)
      Concerns arrangements for a treaty
      meeting with the Indians.
    - LS to J.P. Henderson and Isaac Van Zandt, Houston, Texas, 1844 Apr 16 (Box 5, Folder 272)
      12 p. 25 cm.
      At head of p. 1: Official.
      Concerns the annexation of Texas
      to the United States and the
      attitude of France and Great
      Britain toward it.
    - Positive photostat of LS to Isaac Van Zandt and J. P. Henderson, Houston, 1844 Apr 29 (Box 5, Folder 273)
      2 copies.
      Concerns the annexation of Texas to
      the United States.
  - Texas. Governor, 1857-1859 (Runnels)
    - Land grant to Viktor Bracht, City of Austin, 1858 Mar 8 (Box 5, Folder 274)
      1 p. 37 cm.
  - Texas. Supreme Court
    - Draft of testimonial in favor of Thomas Jefferson Chambers, n.p., n.d. (Box 5, Folder 275)
      Discusses Chamber's ability to
      collect and edit the laws of Spain
      and Mexico in relation to Texas.
  - Throckmorton, James Webb, 1825-1894
    - ALS to Genl. Duncan S. Walker, McKinney, Texas, 1880 May 13 (Box 5, Folder 276)
      1 p. 27.5 cm.
      Concerning Democratic Party
      politics.
  - Travis, William Barret, 1809-1836
    - ALS to Henry Smith, San Felipe, Texas, 1834 Oct 25 (Box 5, Folder 277)
      Discusses some political news.
    - Signed memorandum, Austin, Texas, 1834 Nov 15 (Box 5, Folder 278)
      1 p. 20.5 cm.
      Acting as attorney for the heirs
      of Charles Baird, he has hired a
      negro woman to Ira R. Lewis.
    - ALS to Henry Smith, San Felipe, Texas, 1835 Jul 26 (Box 5, Folder 279)
      Asking to have some printing work
      done.
    - ALS to Henry Smith, San Felipe, Texas, 1835 Aug 5 (Box 5, Folder 280)
      Refers to Travis' participation in
      the raid on Anahuac.
    - ALS to "Andrew Ponton judge & to the Citizens of Gonzales," Commandancy of Bexar, 1836 Feb 23 (Box 5, Folder 281)
      Addressed on verso: To any of the
      inhabitants of Texas.
      Accompanied by negative photograph
      and photostat.
      Request for men to defend the
      Alamo.
    - Photostat (positive) of ALS to "The People of Texas & all Americans in the World", Commandancy of the Alamo, Bexar, 1836 Feb 24 (Box 5, Folder 282)
      Tells of the siege of the Alamo.
  - Tyler, John, 1790-1862
    - ALS to Charles A. Wickliffe, Sherwood Forest, Chas. City County, Virginia, 1848 Nov 20 (Box 5, Folder 283)
      At head of page: Private.
      Accompanied by "A statement of
      what transpired after the passage
      of the joint resolution for the
      Concerns the events relating to the
      annexation of Texas during Tyler's
      last few days in office.
      Enclosed notes.
  - U.S. Consulate. Mexico (City)
    - 2 ALS to Francis M. Dimond, Mexico [City], 1845 Oct 18 (Box 5, Folder 284)
      Second item dated 1845 Nov 22.
      8 p. 32 and 33.5 cm.
      Signed: John Black.
      Discusses current relations between
      the United States and Mexico and
      other recent events.
  - U.S. President, 1841-1845 (Tyler)
    - ALS to C.A. Wickliffe, White Sulphur Springs, Va, 1845 Aug 24 (Box 5, Folder 285)
      Concerns the work towards the
      annexation of Texas.
  - U.S. Quartermaster's dept.
    - "Diary of Genl. Whiting's Tour of Inspection in Texas," Texas., 1851 May-Aug (Box 5, Folder 286)
      Dated 1851 Jun 5 - Aug 14.
      Accompanied by copies of letters
      by Gel. Whiting relating to the
      trip.
      1851 May 2-Aug 22, San Antonio.
      20 p. 32.5 cm.
  - Valdes, Manuel F.
    - ALS to Ira R. Lewis, Victoria, 1845 Oct 17 (Box 5, Folder 287)
      Concerns the legality of Mexican
      land claims.
  - Van Rensselaer, J.R.
    - ALS to I.R. Lewis, New York, N.Y, 1837 May 8 (Box 5, Folder 288)
      Attached: Document certifying an
      account of Matthew McDonough.
      Signed: John Woodward and Matthew
      McDonough.
      1837 May 2, New York City.
      Concerns an account of Samuel Frost
      against James R. Tileston.
  - Ventner, John D.
    - ALS to Ira R. Lewis, San Luis, 1840 Aug 19 (Box 5, Folder 289)
      4 p. with address, 28 cm.
      Relates to the organization of
      the San Luis Company.
  - Viesca, Agustin
    - ALS to Stephen F. Austin, Goliad, Texas, 1835 Nov 11 (Box 5, Folder 290)
      2 p. 26 cm.
      Discusses his recent imprisonment
      and political conditions in Texas.
  - Walker, Robert James, 1801-1869
    - ALS to "Dear Sir," Washington City, 1844 Feb 10 (Box 5, Folder 291)
      and asks the recipient to head a
      Texan expedition to add Santa Fe
      to the dominion of Texas.
  - Ward, William, d. 1836
    - ALS to Messrs. Thompson and Clements, Goliad, Texas, 1836 Feb 20 (Box 5, Folder 292)
      5 p. 31 cm.
      Refusal of request for a letter of
      Henry Smith's which contains
      charges against the Council.
  - Warren, Edward
    - ALS to Henry Warren, Nacogdoches, Texas, 1835 Dec 25 (Box 5, Folder 293)
      Describes his trip to Texas and
      the political situation there.
  - Watson, T.A.
    - ALS to Felix Huston, Texana, 1837 Jan 18 (Box 5, Folder 294)
      Tells of a military operation in
      the Lavaca Bay area.
  - Webb, James, 1792-1856
    - ALS to Ira R. Lewis, Galveston, Texas, 1852 Mar 23 (Box 5, Folder 295)
      Concerns a claim against Gen.
      Lamar.
  - Wharton, John Austin, 1806-1838
    - ALS to Henry Smith, San Felipe, Texas, 1835 Jul 19 (Box 5, Folder 296)
      Concerns the necessity for holding
      a general council.
    - Draft of "Paper circulated by Jno. A. Wharton to call a convention of the people of Texas," Brazoria, Texas, 1835 Aug 9 (Box 5, Folder 297)
      Signed by ninety four citizens.
      At head: This call was published in
      the Texas Republican. Brazoria, Aug
      15, 1835 by F.C. Gray.
    - ALS to "Dear Sir," Brazoria, Texas, 1835 Oct 9 (Box 5, Folder 298)
      Congratulations on being elected
      to represent the jurisdiction of
      Columbia in the Consultation of
      the 15th Oct.
  - Wharton, Sarah Ann (Groce), 1810-1870
    - ALS to Major Lewis, Eagle Island, 183? Dec 26 (Box 5, Folder 299)
      1 p. 17 cm.
      Inviting the Lewis family for a
      visit.
    - ALS to Henry Smith, Nashville, Tenn, 1836 Mar 26 (Box 5, Folder 300)
      Discusses Texan independence.
  - Wharton, William Harris, 1802-1839
    - ALS to Henry Smith, Memphis, Tenn, 1836 Jan 27 (Box 5, Folder 301)
      6 p. 25 cm.
      At head of p. 1: Unofficial.
      Discusses feelings in the United
      States towards Texas.
  - Wightman, Elias R., 1792-1841
    - Draft of letter "To the Board of Land Coms.", Matagorda, 1840 May 9 (Box 5, Folder 302)
      Signed note on docket.
      Concerns his original land grant
      and augmentation certificate.
    - ALS to Col. Lewis, Matagorda, 1840 Jul 2 (Box 5, Folder 303)
      Concerns a dispute over local
      roads.
  - Williams, Samuel May, 1795-1858
    - Power of attorney to Stephen F. Austin, San Felipe de Austin, 1830 Dec 17 (Box 5, Folder 304)
      Signed: Thos Barnett, Samuel M.
      Williams, and two others.
    - ALS to Ira R. Lewis, Galveston, Texas, 1840 Oct 5 (Box 5, Folder 305)
      Letter of introduction of Mr.
      D.C. Kerr.
  - Williamson, Robert McAlpin, 1804-1859
    - ALS to Col. I.R. Lewis, n.p, 1837 Nov 29 (Box 5, Folder 306)
      Concerns legal affairs.
- COLLECTION OF AUTOGRAPHS, WA MSS S-499
  Collection of Autographs of Signers of the Texas
  Declaration of Independence
  ALS, documents and other autographs,
  1820-1852, v.p. Includes
  transcriptions, translations, and
  Streeter's notes scattered throughout.
  70 l., 19-43 cm.
  - Barnett, George Washington, 1793-1848 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Blount, Stephen William, 1808-1890 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brigham, Asa, 1790-1844 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Briscoe, Andrew, 1810-1849 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bunton, John Wheeler, 1807-1879 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Caldwell, Mathew, c.1798-1842 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Clark, William, 1798-1871 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Coleman, Robert M. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Collinsworth, James, 1806-1838 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Ellis, Richard, 1781-1846 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Everitt, Stephen Hendrickson, 1807-1844 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Gaines, James Taylor, 1776-1856 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Gazley, Thomas Jefferson, 1801-1853 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Goodrich, Benjamin Briggs, 1799-1860 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Grimes, Jesse, 1788-1866 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Hardin, Augustine Blackburn, 1797-1871 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Latimer, Albert Hamilton, 1808-1877 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Legrand, Edwin Oswald, 1803-1871 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - McKinney, Collin, 1766-1861 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Maverick, Samuel Augustus, 1803-1870 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Menard, Michel Branamour, 1805-1856 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Menefee, William, 1796-1875 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Moore, John W., 1797-1846 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Navarro, Jose Antonio, 1795-1871 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Parmer, Martin, 1778-1850 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Power, James, 1788-1852 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Roberts, John S., 1796-1871 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Robertson, Sterling Clack, 1785-1842 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Ruiz, Francisco, 1783-1840 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Rusk, Thomas Jefferson, 1802-1856 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Scates, William Bennett, 1802-1882 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Stapp, Elijah, 1783-1843 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Swisher, James Gibson, 1794-1864 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Taylor, Charles Stanfield, 1808-1865 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Waller, Edwin, 1800-1883 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - West, Claiborne, 1800-1866 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Zavala, Lorenzo de, 1788-1836 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Texas Subjects, 1818-1864, WA MSS S-500
  - Castenado, Juan de
    - Copy of reports and diary, Bexar, 1818 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Dated 1818 Sep 16-Nov 22.
      36 p. 30.5 cm.
      Included are reports of Antonio
      Martinez, Jose Sandobal and others.
      Concerns the Champ d'Asile
      expedition of 1818.
  - Chihuahua Navigation Company
    - Documents relating to the founding of the company, v.p, 1828 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      11 p. 26-33.5 cm.
      Typed translation of one document.
  - Coley, Henry
    - DS, New York, 1834 Jan 24 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      7 p. 33 cm.
      Certified by Edward Curtis, 1834
      Feb 7, New York.
      Accompanied by an unsigned memo
      giving further details.
      Sets forth the particulars for an
      expedition to Texas he will make
      for the Galveston Bay and Texas
      Land Company.
  - Lamar, Mirabeau Bonaparte, 1798-1859
    - Indian tribes of Texas (Box 1, Folder 4)
      15 p. 23 cm.
      In the handwriting of Thomas
      Falconer.
      In a bound volume.
      Title from cover.
  - Lasalle City Company
    - Indenture between the Lasalle City Company and Enoch Jones, n.p, 1851 Jul 22 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Granting land to Enoch Jones in
      trust for the San Antonio and
      Mexican Gulf Rail Road Company.
  - Matagorda, Texas
    - 11 documents relating to the founding of Matagorda, Matagorda, 1830-38 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Dated 1830 Aug 1 - 1838 Jun 13.
      56 p. various sizes.
      Signed mostly by Elias Wightman,
      Ira Ingram, and Seth Ingram.
      Contains minutes of meetings,
      records of land sales, and other
      miscellaneous material.
  - Mexico. Ejercito de operaciones sobre Tejas
    - Capitulation of Dec 11, 1835, 1835 Dec 11 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      In English and Spanish.
      Signed Martin Perfecto Cos, Edward
      Burleson and others.
      Terms of surrender by which Cos
      agreed to withdraw troops from
      San Antonio.
  - New-Braunfels (Texas). Office of the Provost Marshal
    - Collection of documents, orders, and miscellaneous papers, New Braunfels, Texas, 1862-64 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Dated 1862 Feb 12 - 1864 Sep 30.
      18 p. 10-35.5 cm.
      Mainly signed by Robert Bechem.
  - Renaud, A.
    - Remarks on Velasco-Galveston, March 1840, 1840 March (Box 1, Folder 9)
      6 p. 22.5 cm.
      Description of the Galveston harbor
      and Rio Brassos [sic].
  - Tagert, Samuel
    - ALS to John Gill, jr., Van Buren, Ark (Box 1, Folder 10)
      2 p. with address, 28 cm.
      Relates to a debt of the Texas firm
      of Coffee, Colville, & Co.
  - Unidentified authors
    - MS notes referring to Texas, n.p., 1830? (Box 1, Folder 11)
      8 p. 20 cm.
      p. 5, 6, and 7: MS diary of a trip
      from New Orleans to Texas dated
      1830 Feb 6 and 11.
      Refers to government, laws, trade,
      geography, and natural resources.
    - Texas and Great Britain. Draft of letter and unsigned notes, 1840 Jul 12 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      12 p. 24 cm.
      The letter contains a description
      of Texas in relation to the esta-
      blishing of a British resident
      there. It is dated Secretary's
      Office, July 12, 1840. The notes
      are mainly concerned with the
      finances of Texas.
    - Emigration to Texas, 1839 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      In Case.
    - Propositions made by sundry individuals of the city of New York ..., New York, 1835 Apr 22 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      4 p. 32.5 cm.
      List of subscribers included.
      Page 4 is a certificate of Texas
      commissioners signed: Wm. H.
      Wharton, S.F. Austin, B.T. Archer.
    - "Something about Texas in 1840" (Box 1, Folder 15)
      2 MS notebooks.
      53 p. 24 cm.
      Account of life in Galveston in
      1840, written by an officer of the
      British Navy.
- Appendix: Streeter's "Catalogue of Texas Manuscripts"
  - "Catalogue of Texas Manuscripts," Parts I-III, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
    2 typescript notebooks, annotated
    in pencil.
    Title from spine.
  - Miscellaneous clippings, correspondence, and notes regarding provenance, 1941-55 (Box 1, Folder 3-5)